myfuture.edu.au 2006-11-09

# myfuture Privacy Statement

myfuture.edu.au Privacy Statement   

1. Introduction

In Australia, collection and handling of personal information is regulated by the Privacy Act 1988. Personal information is basically information or an opinion which can identify you. 

The purpose of this Privacy Statement is to explain how we may collect personal information about you, and how we might use, disclose and handle that personal information.

**_education.au limited_** maintains and hosts this Site for the Department of Education, Science and Training. Any reference to "We" in this Privacy Statement includes a reference to the Department of Education, Science and Training.

| 

---|---  
  
2. Collection of personal information

There are 3 ways in which we may collect your personal information. These are explained below:

> **(a) User ID**
> 
> In order to access some parts of this Site, you will need to select a User ID and a password. 
> 
> Your User ID may be any name you choose, and you may change it and your password at any time. The User ID you choose will determine whether or not you can be identified when you use this Site. For privacy reasons, we encourage you to select a User ID which is not your name. That way, it will be difficult to identify who you are, and may mean that we do not collect personal information about you in this way. However, if you use a User ID which is your actual name, this will mean that we may collect personal information about you.
> 
>   **(b) E-mails and Electronic Forms**
> 
> You may decide to provide us with your email address. If you do have an email address that might identify who you are, for example where your email address contains your name and where you work, remember that this is personal information when you are sending us emails or providing your email address to us.
> 
> **(c) Clickstream Data & Cookies **
> 
> When you visit this Site our server makes a record of your visit and logs the following information:
> 
>   *  your server address 
>   *  your top level domain name (for example .com, .gov, .au, .net, .edu, etc) 
>   *  the time and date of your visit to the website 
>   *  the pages and documents you have accessed or viewed 
>   *  the type of browser you are using
> 

> 
> Generally, this information will identify the computer you are using, rather than identifying you. 
> 
> Similarly, sometimes the administration website uses cookies . A cookie is a small amount of information stored on your computer by our server. This information is sent by your web browser to our server whenever you visit it again.  Cookies are used to remember your browser between page visits. However, the cookie identifies your browser, not you personally. No personal information is stored within the myfuture.edu.au cookies.  
> 

3. How we use your personal information

We will only use your personal information for the purpose for which you provided it to us, except as outlined in this section.

We may use, reproduce, adapt, or retrieve your personal information for statistical purposes (eg to calculate how many people are using this Site). These statistics may be published, but not in a way which will identify any individual. 

The reason we collect statistical information about the use of this Site (whether through cookies, or clickstream data, or through aggregating statistics about users) is that we need this information for:: 

  * website and system administration, including monitoring to prevent security breaches; 
  * maintaining and improving the website; 
  * reporting purposes; 
  * research and development; and 
  * to produce statistics about the traffic on the website.   

4\. Mentoring program

To assist in your use of this Site, you may ask a person you know and trust to be your mentor. Your mentor could be a career guidance counsellor from your school, a teacher, a parent or a friend. If you give your mentor your User ID, this will enable your mentor to access the information you provide to this Site. Please be aware that if you do so, we cannot control how your mentor uses your information. This is why you should only ask someone to be your mentor if you can trust them to keep your personal information private. If you no longer want your mentor to have access to your personal information, you can remove their access rights at any time.

As we cannot control your selection of a mentor or your mentor's use of your personal information, we cannot accept any responsibility for unauthorised use of your personal information by your mentor.

5. How we disclose your information

We will not disclose your personal information without your consent unless authorised or required by law.

6. Personal Information on the website

We will only put your personal information on this Site if it has been collected for this purpose with your knowledge or if you have consented to the disclosure. When giving such consent you should be aware that information put on this Site is accessible to millions of users from all over the world, that it will be indexed by search engines and that it may be copied and used by any web user. This means that, once the information is put on this Site, we will have no control over its subsequent use and disclosure.  

7\. Security of your Personal Information  

We take all reasonable steps to ensure that the information (including personal information) we hold in our servers is not subject to loss, misuse or unauthorised access or alteration. We will continue to hold your personal information but may delete your account and all personal information contained in this account if your account has been inactive for an extended period of time. If you wish us to destroy your personal information you can request us to remove your account [LINK].In accordance with the Terms and Conditions of Use of this Site, however, **_education.au limited_** cannot accept any liability for any loss suffered by you as a result of unauthorised access to this Site. 

This Site does not, however, provide facilities for the secure transmission of information across the Internet. You should be aware that there are inherent risks associated with the transmission of personal information via the Internet. 

You should also note that if you link to another website from this Site, a different privacy and security statement is likely to apply. Therefore, once you leave this Site, you should check the online privacy and security statements of the new website.

Please be aware that you can also protect the security of information you provide to this Site by not disclosing your User ID and password to any other person.  

8\. Access to your personal information

In most cases, the Privacy Act gives you the right to gain access to personal information that we hold about you. All requests for access to your personal information will be handled by our privacy access officer, who can be contacted by writing to the address set out below. This is not, however, intended to cover requests for lost or forgotten passwords and is to be limited to genuine requests for the information which you have provided to this Site.

We will deal with all requests for access to personal information as quickly as possible. Requests for a large amount of information, or information which is not currently in use, may require further time before a response can be given. Please note that we are entitled to charge you the reasonable costs which we incur in complying with such a request for access.

In some cases, consistently with the Privacy Act, we may refuse to give you access to personal information we hold about you. This includes circumstances where giving you access:

  * would have an unreasonable impact on other people's privacy;
  * would prejudice negotiations we are having with you;
  * would prejudice an investigation of unlawful activity; or
  * would prejudice activities carried out by, or for, a law enforcement agency.

If we refuse to give you access we will provide you with reasons for our refusal.

Generally, if you request us to do so we will amend any personal information about you held by us which is inaccurate, incomplete or out of date. If we disagree with you about the accuracy, completeness or currency of a record of your personal information held by us, we will take reasonable steps to associate with that record a statement to the effect that you claim this to be the case, if you request us to do so.

9\. When to check this privacy policy

We may make changes to this privacy policy from time to time, so you should check it each time you visit this Site.

10\. How to contact us  

We want to develop a long and trusted relationship with you. If at any time you:

  * have any questions regarding this Privacy Statement, the practices of this Site or dealings with this Site; or 
  * if you are concerned that we have breached your privacy and wish to make a complaint,

> please contact us at:
> 
> (a) Contact Us; or
> 
> (b) Career Services Manager   
>        _ **education.au limited  
>        **_182 Fullarton Road  
>       DULWICH  SA  5065; or
> 
> (c) Department of Education, Science and Training  
>       Director  
>       Career Education Section  
>       GPO Box 9880  
>       16-18 Mort Street  
>       CANBERRA  ACT  2600; or
> 
> (d) phone (02) 6240 8111

If you would like to know more about your rights under Australian privacy laws, please see the Privacy Commissioner's website at [www.privacy.gov.au](http://www.privacy.gov.au/).

This privacy policy was last updated on 28 August 2003.
